Guide to the Yale Debates and Disputations Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale debates and disputations collection
1794-1834
RU 139
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
The collection consists of Yale student notebooks, notes, and compositions documenting debates and disputations.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 47 (YRG 47), Collections documenting teaching and learning in Yale academic programs.
Arrangement
Arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of Yale student notebooks, notes, and compositions documenting debates and disputations.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Debates and debating; Debates; Yale College (1718-1887) -- Students
- Debates and disputations, Accession 19ND-A-389
  - Unidentified
    - Twelve Disputations, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Haskel, Daniel Y.1802
    - Disputes and Compositions, 1800-1803 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adams, Ebenezer B.
    - Three Debates, 1833-1834 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Smith, David Y.1795
    - Three notebooks of disputes, 1794-1795 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Baldwin, Hezekiah H. 1790-1826, Y.1810
    - Senior disputes, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Unknown
    - "Notes from the instructions given by Dr. Dwight to the Senior Class in Yale College", 1812-1813 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Couch, Jesup N. Y.1802
    - Book of disputations, 1801 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Notes from the disputes of the Senior Class, 1814-1815 (Box 2, Folder 8)